<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Jekyll Bootstrap-3</title>
        <description>Jekyll Bootstrap-3 - Name Lastname</description>
        <link>http://username.github.io</link>
        <link>http://username.github.io</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2014-08-03T08:44:48-07:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2014-08-03T08:44:48-07:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>Solar Facility Commissioning with Custom Data Monitoring Website</title>
                <description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our staff worked with a solar power provider to develop and implement a web-based monitoring system for use at 3 of their new solar power plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Completely customized Web-based monitoring of three solar facilities on one site&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Power meter, inverter and string box information&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Weather station information monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Three levels of access, Public, Customer and Maintenance&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Automated billing documentation generation and dissemination&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Alarm notifications via email and text message&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Automated updates of on-site signage indicating power produced and emissions saved&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Technology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;ASP.NET&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Red Lion Data Station Plus&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;SQL Server&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;B&amp;amp;B Electronic Modbus Converters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our staff met with the operations team for a start-up solar power provider to discuss a developing a web-based monitoring system. The goal was to provide a low-cost, high functionality monitoring system for 3 facilities between 1 and 3 MW each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We utilized Red Lion Data Station Plus units at each facility to collect data from field equipment and send it via cellular modem to a centralized database. This data was then displayed using trend controls on the site which allowed users to select date ranges, filter on equipment types and specific pieces of equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If someone accessed the site without login credentials they were presented with a graph of power production limited to 30 days prior and older. If they accessed the site and were one of the customers or the owners of the facility where the plant was located they could see current overall production data and weather station information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the user was part of the solar company or their maintenance team they had access to all current production data for all equipment and weather station information. They could also manage what alarms sent notifications, who received billing information and administer users of the system. They also had access to a trend allowing them to add any datapoints from the site for completely customized data analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/solar-facility-and-monitoring-website</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/solar-monitoring-website</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-08-06T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Conversion from Wonderware Historian to FactoryTalk Historian</title>
                <description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of years ago a leading diatomaceous earth processing company worked with our staff to install Wonderware InSQL (now Historian) along with Incuity (now VantagePoint) at a number of it’s facilities. As other facilities began adopting these systems they used VantagePoint after Rockwell Automation purchased Incuity Software and FactoryTalk Historian as it was integrated and licensed to work with VantagePoint out of the box. This prompted an ugrade of the systems at all of their facilities to reduce support costs and maintain corporate standards. This upgrade included importing existing data from Wonderware InSQL/Historian to FactoryTalk Historian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Technology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Wonderware Historian/InSQL&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Incuity/VantagePoint&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;FactoryTalk Historian&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;SQL Server&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Allen Bradley ControlLogix PLCs&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Allen Bradley CompactLogix PLCs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All facilities standardized on the latest versions of VantagePoint&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All facilities standardized on the lastest versions of FactoryTalk Historian&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Upgraded to a new FactoryTalk Historian installation with no loss of data&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All facilities were configured for automatic backups of data and configurations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our staff was familiar with the company’s existing systems having implemented them originally. We worked on new server hardware at each facility and installed all of the software components. From there we exported all of the Incuity components and imported them into VantagePoint, configured communications between FactoryTalk Historian and various PLCs and configured communications between VantagePoint and FactoryTalk Historian. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next we went through the existing Wonderware InSQL/Historian configuration and set up all of the tags to be imported into FactoryTalk Historian. Once imported we verified data was coming across correctly from the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally we exported data from the existing Wonderware InSQL/Historian server and developed scripts to automatically import the data into FactoryTalk Historian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client was then able to use the new VantagePoint and FactoryTalk Historian system to view new data and all data that had been collected on the old system with a seamless transition and was able to decommission and remove the old server at each facility.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/wonderware-to-factorytalk-historian-conversion</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/wonderware-to-fthistorian-conversion</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Wonderware Historian Implementation for Environmental Impact Reporting</title>
                <description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A small mine in Nevada required automatic pollution reporting and data collection to meet EPA regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Automated daily reporting of pollutant use and discharge directly to the State Department of Environmental Protection&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Reporting functionality allowing regulators or mine personnel to review reports from any day after the system was implemented&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Process data now stored in a Historian allowing for better data analysis and tracking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Technology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Wonderware Historian
	&lt;li&gt;Wonderware Historian Client
	&lt;li&gt;SQL Server


&lt;h3&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
A small gold mine outside of Elko Nevada was required by the State Department of Environmental Protection to submit daily reports detailing pollutant use and discharge along with some process data to verify the readings.

We installed and configured Wonderware Historian to collect and store process data along with Wonderware Historian Client to populate an Excel report at the end of each day. When the report was created we ran a SQL Server stored procedure to print the Excel report to PDF and upload it to the Department of Environmental Protection&#39;s FTP server.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/gold-mine-wonderware-historian</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/gold-mine-ww-historian</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-08-04T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Multiple solar sites producing 109MW</title>
                <description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our staff worked with a leading solar power provider to develop and implement a standardized SCADA system for use at new solar power plants. We commissioned 16 plants producing 109MW of solar power using this system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Reduced development time for future plants&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Standardized graphics, data structures and network topologies reduced maintenance and training requirements for future plants&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Changes to the system at newer facilities could easily be pushed out to all existing facilities&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Systems could be operated and maintained remotely&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Automated reporting for power production, billing and plant performance including alarms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Technology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Wonderware System Platform
	&lt;li&gt;Wonderware InTouch&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Wonderware Historian&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;OSI PI Historian&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;SQL Server&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;N-Tron networking equipment&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Moxa Modbus communication equipment&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Cisco ASA Firewalls&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Juniper Firewalls&lt;/li&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
Our staff met with the SCADA operations team for a large solar power provider to discuss a standardized system built using Wonderware System Platform. The goal was to build objects for the various pieces of equipment at a solar plant, inverters, breakers, power meters, etc., to enable rapid deployment of SCADA systems for new facilities. 

As part of developing the system we developed a standardized naming convention for the facilities and all of the datapoints to allow a script to populate a centralized OSI PI Historian with data from each facility.

After completion of the initial development future systems took less time as the SCADA system was built using existing objects and commissioning was basically complete after I/O and communication verifications.

With remote access to each facility we also reduced support time and costs by allowing our staff to login to each system to make any neccessary modifications, including updating older facilities with any objects developed for newer facilities.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/solar-109MW</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/solar-109MW</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-08-03T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>PLC5 to ControlLogix Conversion for Large Frozen Potato Product Manufacturing Facility</title>
                <description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large potato processing facility in central Idaho replaced Allen Bradley PLC5 processors with ControlLogix and CompactLogix processors and wanted to ensure the new logic conformed to corporate programming standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Facility upgraded to modern hardware&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Logic was updated to current corporate programming standards&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Updating logic to new standards required no unplanned downtime&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Technology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Allen Bradley PLC5&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Allen Bradley ControlLogix PLCs&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Allen Bradley CompactLogix PLCs&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Rockwell Automation RSLogix5&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Rockwell Automation RSLogix5000&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The facility’s maintenance staff performed the PLC5 to ControlLogix/CompactLogix conversion and did not have the time to update the logic, addressing, etc. to current corporate programming standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our staff reviewed all of the affected logic and created new tags to match current naming conventions. From there we did a line-by-line upgrade of the logic (off-site) to match current standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During a scheduled downtime for cleaning and other upgrades, we downloaded the new code into the PLCs and spent time on-site verifying the new logic adjacent to the old logic. As the various routines were verfied we updated the I/O mapping to use the new tags and deleted the old tags and logic from the PLC. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we had completed verifying all of the logic the PLC was upgraded to current standards and required no unplanned downtime as part of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/potato-PLC5-conversion</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/PLC5-To-ControlLogix-Conversion</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-08-03T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Energy Bar Conveyor Speed Sync</title>
                <description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An energy bar manufacturing facility had a number of standalone pieces of equipment on which they wanted the ability to set a global, synchronized speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Stand alone equipment now integrated with a PLC to provide the capability for full-line automation&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;8 pieces of equipment with local control can now be operated from one operator interface&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Recipe management capabilities enable operators to configure speeds for various products and select them on the fly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Technology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Allen Bradley Powerflex VFDs&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Allen Bradley CompactLogix PLC&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Allen Bradley Panelview Plus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The client’s existing process line consisted of 8 stand-alone machines taking raw ingredients, forming them into bars, enrobing in chocolate and drying them prior to entering the packaging line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each of these machines has a conveyor with a locally configurable speed for each piece of equipment. Operators were spending a signficant amount of time adjusting the speeds for each piece of equipment when changing products, resulting in issues when the speeds were not exactly the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We implemented a system using Allen Bradley CompactLogix PLC and Panelview Plus to communicate with Powerflex 4 and 5 VFDs installed on each piece of equipment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The local control capability for each machine was replaced by a screen on the Panelview Plus allowing the operators to set a desired speed and the PLC calculating the required values for each drive based on its conveyor properties and gear ratios. The operators were also given the capability to configure speeds for various products giving them a drop-down menu to cut changeover times essentially to zero with respect to adjusting the speed of the line.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/energy-bar-conveyor-sync</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/energy-bar-conveyor-sync</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-08-02T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Energy Bar Mixer Replacement</title>
                <description>&lt;h3&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An energy bar manufacturing facility’s raw ingredient mixer had a faulty Cutler Hammer PLC and operator interface. We reverse-engineered the control logic and upgraded the Cutler Hammer equipment with an Allen Bradley Micrologix PLC and Panelview Plus operator interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Controls brought up to modern standards&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Safety controls re-enabled as part of upgrade&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Recipe management capabilities implemented as part of the upgrade&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Stand-alone equipment now capable of being integrated into an overall process control system&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Customer has updated documentation and copies of all programs and logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Technology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Allen Bradley Micrologix 1100&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Allen Bradley Panelview Plus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Solution&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We met with the client to discuss their existing system and how both the PLC and operator interface were failing due to age and general wear and tear. The mixer had been installed when the plant was first opened in the early 90’s and no software was available for the Cutler Hammer PLC or operator interface 20 years after installation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We worked with the plant operators to understand and develop a control philosophy for the mixer. One major issue with the existing hardware was that some of the inputs to the PLC from safety devices had failed. These issues were resolved with the upgraded PLC. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The operators also requested recipe management functionality, allowing them to easily configure various mixing steps depending on the product being produced. We implemented a screen in the HMI allowing them to configure a handful of steps with various mixing speeds and times which allowed them to reduce a large amount of over and under-mixing caused by manually timing steps using the old system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new system was commissioned, operators were trained and the process was back up and running by lunchtime. The client now has updated copies of all documentation putting them in a better position for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/energy-bar-mixer</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/energy-bar-mixer</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-08-01T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
